Vengeance thy name is woman
I Spit on Your Grave: Déjà Vu is a thriller,
horror film directed by Meir Zarchi.
Following her rape, Jennifer Hills wrote a bestselling account of her ordeal and of the controversial trial in
which she was accused of taking the law into her own hands and brutally killing her assailants.
In the small town where the rape and revenge took place, the relatives of the rapists she killed are
furious that the court declared her not guilty and resolve to take justice into their own hands.
Jennifer Hills, played by Camille Keaton.
Christy Hills, played by Jamie Bernadette.
Becky, played by Maria Olsen.
Herman, played by Jim Tavaré.
Kevin, played by Jonathan Peacy.
Scotty, played by Jeremy Ferdman.
I Spit on Your Grave (originally titled Day of the Woman) is a 1978 American
rape and revenge film written and directed by Meir Zarchi.
The film tells the story of Jennifer Hills (Camille Keaton), a fiction writer based in New York
City who exacts revenge on her four tormentors who gang rape and leave her for dead.
I Spit on Your Grave is noted for its controversial depiction of extreme graphic violence,
particularly the lengthy depictions of gang rape, that take up 30 minutes of its runtime.
During its wider release, it was branded a "video nasty" in the United Kingdom,
and was a target of censorship by film commissioning bodies.
Film critic Roger Ebert became one of the most notable detractors of I
Spit on Your Grave, calling it "a vile bag of garbage".
The film remains highly controversial to this day, even being
considered to be one of the worst films ever made.
For some, it is this controversy which has led to
it being deemed a cult classic.
Despite the controversy and overwhelmingly negative reviews, the
performance of Keaton was praised by critics.
In 2010, I Spit on Your Grave was included in Time
magazine's "Top 10 Ridiculously Violent Movies".
The film spawned a 2010 remake, which has since spawned two sequels of its own: I Spit on
Your Grave 2 (2013), and I Spit on Your Grave III: Vengeance Is Mine (2015).
A direct sequel, I Spit on Your Grave: Deja Vu, was released
in 2019 with Zarchi and Keaton both returning.
In her memoir Inside Out, Demi Moore confirmed that she is the scantily
clad woman on the film's poster with her back turned.
The film explores themes of rape, sequel, revenge, rape and revenge.
The tone is dark and intense.